<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Purchase on SECURIFIED</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/purchase/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Purchase on SECURIFIED</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.150.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/purchase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Defending your Finances in the Digital Realm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/finance/</guid>
      <description>A brief guide on digital payments.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="credit-card-theft">Credit Card Theft</h3>
<p>Stolen credit/debit card numbers are sold for mere dollars on the black market. This is because they are so ubiquitous as they are lost in data breaches all the time.</p>
<h3 id="privacycom">Privacy.com</h3>
<p><a href="https://privacy.com">Privacy.com</a> allows the creation of virtual visa/mastercard gift cards that function like a debit card. This service is free as Privacy.com takes a portion of the fee that is payed to the card company (Visa or Mastercard) by the merchant. There is also a paid option with added benefits.</p>
<p>For one-off purchases, there are one-time use cards that close after they have been used. Meaning that even if the number is stolen it can&rsquo;t be used again. There are also multi-use cards with finely customizable spending and transactions limits. Also, each of these cards can only be used for one merchant. So if a card is used at merchant A, it can&rsquo;t then be used for merchant B, as it is already locked to merchant A. This helps minimize the damage a stolen card number may cause, as it would have to be used at the same place. Cards can also be closed or paused at any time.</p>
<p>Privacy.com is a privacy and security focused company with a great track record and a good privacy policy that limits sharing of personal data.</p>
<h3 id="bank-accounts">Bank Accounts</h3>
<p>A similar topic is securing your bank account access. It should have a completely unique password, different from any other website. Enable multifactor authentication if it is supported. For security questions (eg: what is your mothers maiden name?), do not enter the true information as this can be trivially guessed, found online, or learned through social engineering. Instead, use random answers (eg: What is your home town? &ldquo;New York&rdquo;) and save it in a password manager. Security questions are easily guessed or figured out by attackers, so they should not be the &ldquo;true&rdquo; answer. While this may seem like an odd thing to do, it is increasingly recommended to protect accounts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
