<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Securified</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://securified.net/" />
  <link rel="self" href="https://securified.net/index.xml" />
  <subtitle>Recent content on Securified</subtitle>
  <id>https://securified.net/</id>
  <generator uri="http://gohugo.io" version="0.121.2">Hugo</generator>
  <language>en-us</language>
  <updated>2022-08-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Securified</name>
    
  </author>
  <rights>© Securified 2024</rights>
      <entry>
        <title>A Smörgåsbord of Messengers</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://securified.net/messengers/" />
        <id>https://securified.net/messengers/</id>
        <published>2022-08-03T00:00:00Z</published>
        <updated>2022-08-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">Privacy and security focused messenger showdown.</summary>
          <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>TL;DR: Signal is the best messenger/calling app. Every other messenger has design flaws that affect user security and privacy. Signal is widely regarded as the most secure and private messenger currently available.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h3 id="what-makes-a-good-messenger">What Makes a Good Messenger</h3>
<p>A messenger that respects user privacy and is secure by modern standards, needs to meet a few criteria:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The messenger should not collect data about it&rsquo;s users beyond what is required to function.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.ibm.com/topics/end-to-end-encryption">End-to-end encryption</a> needs to be used to ensure messages/calls can not be viewed by anyone other than intended recipients.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The <a href="https://www.fortinet.com/resources/cyberglossary/what-is-cryptography">cryptography</a> used for the end-to-end encryption needs to be implemented properly using audited, reputable, and verifiable protocols.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<ol start="4">
<li>
<p>Message/call <a href="https://hls.harvard.edu/dept/its/what-is-metadata/">metadata</a> should be protected and private.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It needs to be secure and private by <a href="https://securified.net/bydefault/"><em>default</em></a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Governments should not be able to force those running the messenger to break the encryption or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Backdoor_(computing)">backdoor</a> the software.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It should support basic features: messaging, voice calling, video calling, and file sending.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Being <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/topics/open-source/what-is-open-source">open source</a> is an additional plus.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Many messengers meet some of these criteria, but not all.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="signal-messenger">Signal Messenger</h3>
<p><a href="https://signal.org">Signal</a> is a cross-platform end-to-end encrypted messaging/calling app. It can be installed on phones and computers and supports instant messaging, voice calls, video calls, sending files, taking/sending pictures/videos snapchat style, and much <a href="https://support.signal.org/hc/en-us/sections/360001602792-Signal-Messenger-Features">more</a>.</p>
<p>Signal <a href="https://signal.org/legal/#privacy-policy">does not track its users</a>. The only info Signal knows about you is the <a href="https://yewtu.be/watch?v=Nj3YFprqAr8&amp;t=894s"><em>phone number</em></a> used to register, the account <em>registration date</em>, and the <em>last time you used Signal</em>.</p>
<p>Signal is open and transparent about what government requests <a href="https://signal.org/bigbrother/">they receive</a>. It is open source and all of its code is freely viewable <a href="https://github.com/signalapp">here</a>. Signal is ran by the 501(c)(3) non-profit <a href="https://signalfoundation.org/">Signal Foundation</a>, and is funded by <a href="https://www.signal.org/donate/">donations and grants</a>. It has been independently <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2016/1013.pdf">audited</a> by third party companies to check for vulnerabilities and to verify trustworthiness.</p>
<h4 id="some-of-the-features-signal-has">Some of the features Signal has:</h4>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.ibm.com/topics/end-to-end-encryption">End-to-end encryption</a>: Ensures message/call content can not be viewed by any unintended parties, including the Signal Foundation itself. It uses the audited and reputable <a href="https://engineering.mindlinksoft.com/end-to-end-encryption-with-the-signal-protocol/">Signal Protocol</a> developed by the Signal Foundation for end-to-end encryption.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.signal.org/blog/asynchronous-security/">Perfect Forward Secrecy</a>: This ensures that if the <a href="https://medium.com/codeclan/what-are-encryption-keys-and-how-do-they-work-cc48c3053bd6">encryption key</a> of one message is compromised, other messages can not be decrypted and viewed with that same key.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://signal.org/blog/sealed-sender/">Sealed Sender</a>: This is used to conceal <a href="https://hls.harvard.edu/dept/its/what-is-metadata/">metadata</a>. Signal protects metadata better than all other messengers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://support.signal.org/hc/en-us/articles/360007060632">Safety Numbers</a>: Used to verify you are communicating with who you think you are.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://signal.org/blog/signal-private-group-system/">Private Groups</a>: A private group chat/calling system. The Signal Foundation has no record of who is in a group chat/call, the name of the group, or the group avatar. This is in stark contrast to other messengers where all this is viewable by the service.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="signal-and-phone-numbers">Signal and Phone Numbers</h4>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>Signal requires a phone number for registration and use. This raises a privacy concern for some as anyone you message in Signal can see your phone number. This can be partially solved by using a <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/712588/what-is-a-burner-phone-and-when-should-you-use-one/">burner phone</a> or <a href="https://www.voip.com/">VoIP</a> number when registering with Signal. Signal has said they are working on adding usernames that may replace phone numbers.</p>
<p>Enable registration lock and <a href="https://support.signal.org/hc/en-us/articles/360007059792-Registration-Lock">set a pin</a> in Signal. This will require a pin to be entered before the same number can be registered with Signal again, helping to prevent your Signal account from getting stolen.</p>
<p>Due to the secure way Signal has been designed, messages are not backed up or stored on the Signal servers. This means when installing Signal on a different device, you will need to <a href="https://support.signal.org/hc/en-us/articles/360007059752-Backup-and-Restore-Messages">transfer</a> messages to the new devices.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<hr>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<h3 id="textingsms">Texting/SMS</h3>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SMS">SMS</a>/<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multimedia_Messaging_Service">MMS</a> (commonly referred to as &ldquo;texting&rdquo;), and phone calling is the most common form of communication, but it is neither <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/709373/why-sms-text-messages-arent-private-or-secure/">secure</a> nor <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/columnist/2016/04/16/texting-texts-security-hacking/83118320/">private</a>.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>Your <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_United_States_wireless_communications_service_providers">cell carrier</a> can read your messages/phone calls due to the lack of <a href="https://www.ibm.com/topics/end-to-end-encryption">end-to-end encryption</a>. Some carriers encrypt part of the journey the message/call data takes, but only between the <a href="https://www.rokacom.com/are-text-messages-encrypted%5D">phone and cell tower</a>. They then decrypt the data at the cell tower and are able to view its content. They <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/technolog/how-long-do-wireless-carriers-keep-your-data-120367">store</a> this decrypted message/phone data for varying lengths of time, up to <a href="https://news.law.fordham.edu/jcfl/2016/06/02/cell-phone-forensics-powerful-tools-wielded-by-federal-investigators/">seven years</a>.</p>
<p>Every second your phone is online and connected to a cell tower your cell carrier is <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/10/technology/cellphone-tracking-law-enforcement.html">aware of your location</a> to within <a href="https://www.hgexperts.com/expert-witness-articles/cell-phone-triangulation-the-basics-36172">~100 meters</a>. This valuable location data is <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/402043/can-anyone-really-track-my-phones-precise-location/">sold</a> to bounty hunters, advertising agencies, and the government.</p>
<p>Texting is especially susceptible to <a href="https://cybersecurityventures.com/sim-swap-fraud-the-latest-battle-in-the-war-for-your-identity/">sim swapping</a>. This is where a cybercriminal gets control of your cellphone number through social engineering. What is social engineering? Cisco <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/what-is-social-engineering.html">defines it as</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>At its core, social engineering is not a cyber attack. Instead, social engineering is all about the psychology of persuasion: It targets the mind like your old school grifter or con man. The aim is to gain the trust of targets, so they lower their guard, and then encourage them into taking unsafe actions such as divulging personal information or clicking on web links or opening attachments that may be malicious.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sim swapping attacks can be devastating, leading to <a href="https://threatpost.com/sharp-sim-swapping-spike-losses/178358/">drained bank accounts</a>, stolen tax returns, and identity theft. The FBI Internet Crime Complaint Center received complaints totaling losses of <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/Media/Y2022/PSA220208">$68 million</a> in 2021 due to sim swapping. These losses are due to many online account using sms for signing-in, multifactor, and/or password resets. Once an attacker has control of your phone number, that can use it receive <a href="https://privacypros.io/u2f/sim-swapping/">password reset links</a> for these accounts.</p>
<p>Unfortunately there are no good safeguards your can put up to protect from sim swapping. This is why text-based authentication and multifactor should be completely avoided. An account secured with sms MFA is hardly any better than not having any MFA.</p>
<p>Please, do not use text or phone based sign-in or multifactor authentication to secure any accounts of importance.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="imessage">iMessage</h3>
<p><a href="https://support.apple.com/messages">iMessage</a> is an instant messenger owned by <a href="https://www.apple.com/">Apple</a> that supports instant messaging, voice/video calling, and file sending.</p>
<p>The first knock against it is that it is not cross platform, it is only available on Apple devices. It is also closed source, does not have <a href="https://plzh4x.me/2018/04/07/cryptanalysis-of-the-imessage-protocol/">perfect forward secrecy</a>, does not <a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/16/09/29/apple-acknowledges-tracking-imessage-metadata-and-sharing-it-with-law-enforcement">protect metadata</a> and shares the metadata they collect with law-enforcement.</p>
<p>While iMessage does have end-to-end encryption, it has been implemented <a href="https://plzh4x.me/2018/04/07/cryptanalysis-of-the-imessage-protocol/">poorly</a> and is not secure. To make matters worse, if iMessage is being backed up with iCloud (which it is by default), Apple is able to see the backed-up messages. This is because iCloud backups are not <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/710509/apples-imessage-is-secure...-unless-you-have-icloud-enabled/">end-to-end encrypted</a>. The reason iCloud backup does not have end-to-end encryption? Because the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-apple-fbi-icloud-exclusive/exclusive-apple-dropped-plan-for-encrypting-backups-after-fbi-complained-sources-idUSKBN1ZK1CT">fbi complained</a> when Apple was going to enable it. :unamused:</p>
<p>Apple has tried backdooring iMessage by adding a client side <a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2021/08/apple-adds-a-backdoor-to-imesssage-and-icloud-storage.html">scanning service</a> to iMessage that would scan messages for &ldquo;bad&rdquo; material and report it. Although not currently implemented, there has been talk again about adding it.</p>
<p>While iMessage is convenient on apple devices, it should not be used due to its many downsides, poor encryption and lack of cross-platform support.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="whatsapp">Whatsapp</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/">Whatsapp</a> is a instant messenger owned by the data harvester/ad tech company Meta (Facebook&rsquo;s new parent company). It supports instant messaging, voice/video calling, and file sending.</p>
<p>Although Whatsapp has end-to-end encryption and is not able to view message contents, metadata is <a href="https://www.getsession.org/blog/whatsapp-privacy-policy">tracked</a> aggressively. Their <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/legal/privacy-policy/?lang=en">privacy policy</a> shows that Whatsapp has been incorporated into the massive data harvesting operation of their parent company, Facebook.</p>
<p>Here is just <em>some</em> of the data they say they <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/legal/privacy-policy/?lang=en">collect</a>
from their privacy policy:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>..we collect information about your activity on our Services..this includes information about your activity..log files, and diagnostic, crash, website, and performance logs and reports..when you registered to use our Services; the features you use like our messaging, calling, Status, groups (including group name, group picture, group description), payments or business features; profile photo, &ldquo;about&rdquo; information; whether you are online, when you last used our Services (your &ldquo;last seen&rdquo;); and when you last updated your &ldquo;about&rdquo; information..device and connection-specific information when you install, access, or use our Services. This includes information such as hardware model, operating system information, battery level, signal strength, app version, browser information, mobile network, connection information (including phone number, mobile operator or ISP), language and time zone, IP address, device operations information, and identifiers..precise location information from your device.. [and] ..cookies..</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Facebook markets Whatsapp as a privacy messenger, but after looking at their privacy policy, it clearly is not.</p>
<p>Further, a propublica <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/how-facebook-undermines-privacy-protections-for-its-2-billion-whatsapp-users">article</a> talks about the monitoring and censorship that Whatsapp does on messages:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>WhatsApp has more than 1,000 contract workers.. [who] ..use special Facebook software to sift through millions of private messages, images and videos. They pass judgment on whatever flashes on their screen..</p>
<p>The workers have access to only a subset of WhatsApp messages — those flagged by users and automatically forwarded to the company as possibly abusive. The review is one element in a broader monitoring operation in which the company also reviews material that is not encrypted, including data about the sender and their account.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/personal-finance/040915/how-whatsapp-makes-money.asp">$19 billion</a> is how much Facebook payed for Whatsapp in 2014. Yet, Whatsapp is free to download and does not have ads. In order to make Whatsapp profitable, Facebook collects data about its over 2 billion users and sells ads about the data it collects.</p>
<p>Whatsapp, marketed as a privacy focused messenger is not private in the slightest. It heavily tracks its users and is invaluable to Facebook data harvesting. Whatsapp should be avoided.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="telegram">Telegram</h3>
<p><a href="https://telegram.org/">Telegram</a> is a cross-platform instant messenger based in <a href="https://telegram.org/faq#q-where-is-telegram-based">Dubai</a>, United Arab Emirates. It supports instant messaging, voice/video calling, and file sending.</p>
<p>Telegram does not use end-to-end encryption by <a href="https://telegram.org/faq#q-why-not-just-make-all-chats-secret">default</a>, therefore the Telegram servers, and anyone able to capture messages, are able to view the message contents. There is a feature called <a href="https://telegram.org/faq#secret-chats">Secret Chats</a> that enables end-to-end encryption, but only for the chat it was enabled for. The encryption used is their own custom un-audited <a href="https://core.telegram.org/mtproto">protocol</a> that has had major flaws in the past, and many cryptographers call <a href="https://buttondown.email/cryptography-dispatches/archive/cryptography-dispatches-the-most-backdoor-looking/">&ldquo;weird&rdquo;</a>.</p>
<p>Telegram collects metadata about their users according to their <a href="https://telegram.org/privacy#5-2-safety-and-security">privacy policy</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>..we may collect metadata such as your IP address, devices and Telegram apps you&rsquo;ve used, history of username changes, etc. If collected, this metadata can be kept for 12 months maximum.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Like Signal, a phone number is used for registering and signing in. Unlike Signal, the server code is <a href="https://telegram.org/faq#q-can-i-get-telegram-39s-server-side-code">not</a> open source.</p>
<p>Telegram is not recommended due to end-to-end encryption not being enabled by default, its metadata collection and the un-audited custom protocol they use.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="session">Session</h3>
<p><a href="https://getsession.org/">Session</a> is an up and coming messenger that has many promising features, but is not yet ready for general use.</p>
<p>A few things currently wrong with it are that it doesn&rsquo;t have perfect forward secrecy, message delivery is slow and unreliable, it is based in Australia where encryption/privacy laws are bad, and it is based on their own weird <a href="https://oxen.io/">cryptocurrency/blockchain</a> and <a href="https://lokinet.org/">onion network</a>.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<hr>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>Not all messengers are created equal; Many should be avoided outright. Some more messengers to not use due to bad security and privacy are Facebook Messenger (even worse security than Whatsapp), Snapchat (bad privacy, snaps not actually deleted, lacking encryption), WeChat (Chinese have access to everything sent) and Marco Polo (lacking encryption, share personal data with third parties).</p>
<p>Signal is different. It has been designed from the ground up taking great care to protect user security and privacy through technological means. While not perfect, it is the current best option for a private and secure messenger.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
]]></content>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <title>By Default </title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://securified.net/bydefault/" />
        <id>https://securified.net/bydefault/</id>
        <published>2022-07-24T00:00:00Z</published>
        <updated>2022-07-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">The importance of privacy and security by default.</summary>
          <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="private-and-secure-by-default">Private and Secure by Default</h3>
<p>Privacy and security are not something the general public regularly thinks or cares about. Because of this, the digital items and services we use need to be private and secure by <em>default</em>. However, the average person does not care or might not be aware that the item or service they use needs to be configured differently in order to to make them private and secure.</p>
<p>An example of this is Telegram, which does not have end-to-end encryption enabled by default. Instead it must be enabled in settings. Unfortunately Telegram is often touted as &ldquo;a secure messenger&rdquo;, but due to end-to-end encryption not being enabled by default, most people who use it have only a placebo security.</p>
<p>This is why choosing apps and services that are private and secure by default is critical. Those recommending products and services should recommend ones that adhere to this, and those designing the programs and services should create them to be private and secure, by default.</p>
]]></content>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <title>Defending your Finances in the Digital Realm</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://securified.net/finance/" />
        <id>https://securified.net/finance/</id>
        <published>2022-05-02T00:00:00Z</published>
        <updated>2022-05-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">A brief guide on digital payments.</summary>
          <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="credit-card-theft">Credit Card Theft</h3>
<p>Stolen credit/debit card numbers are sold for mere dollars on the black market. This is because they are so ubiquitous as they are lost in data breaches all the time.</p>
<h3 id="privacycom">Privacy.com</h3>
<p><a href="https://privacy.com">Privacy.com</a> allows the creation of virtual visa/mastercard gift cards that function like a debit card. This service is free as Privacy.com takes a portion of the fee that is payed to the card company (Visa or Mastercard) by the merchant. There is also a paid option with added benefits.</p>
<p>For one-off purchases, there are one-time use cards that close after they have been used. Meaning that even if the number is stolen it can&rsquo;t be used again. There are also multi-use cards with finely customizable spending and transactions limits. Also, each of these cards can only be used for one merchant. So if a card is used at merchant A, it can&rsquo;t then be used for merchant B, as it is already locked to merchant A. This helps minimize the damage a stolen card number may cause, as it would have to be used at the same place. Cards can also be closed or paused at any time.</p>
<p>Privacy.com is a privacy and security focused company with a great track record and a good privacy policy that limits sharing of personal data.</p>
<h3 id="bank-accounts">Bank Accounts</h3>
<p>A similar topic is securing your bank account access. It should have a completely unique password, different from any other website. Enable multifactor authentication if it is supported. For security questions (eg: what is your mothers maiden name?), do not enter the true information as this can be trivially guessed, found online, or learned through social engineering. Instead, use random answers (eg: What is your home town? &ldquo;New York&rdquo;) and save it in a password manager. Security questions are easily guessed or figured out by attackers, so they should not be the &ldquo;true&rdquo; answer. While this may seem like an odd thing to do, it is increasingly recommended to protect accounts.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
]]></content>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <title>IoT: The &#39;S&#39; is for Security</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://securified.net/iot/" />
        <id>https://securified.net/iot/</id>
        <published>2021-11-28T00:00:00Z</published>
        <updated>2021-11-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">An analysis on the lack of IoT Security.</summary>
          <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="iot-insecurity">IoT Insecurity</h3>
<p>The joke about IoT is that the &lsquo;S&rsquo; is for Security. There is no &lsquo;S&rsquo; in IoT, hence there is no security.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.oracle.com/internet-of-things/what-is-iot/">Internet of things (IoT)</a>, consists of all the physical devices and appliances that are internet connected (Alexa devices, smart lights, cars, thermostats, industrial machinery, cameras, doorbells, smart fridges and garage doors to name a few).</p>
<p>Many of these devices do not receive updates, let alone security updates, once they leave the factory. This means that when a vulnerability is discovered for one of these devices, it will not get fixed. A hacked smart fridge can lead to your whole home network becoming compromised, meaning internet activity can be captured and manipulated. That cheap internet security camera might not seem like such a good deal when it turns out it doesn&rsquo;t get updates and has been hacked into and is now being used to spy on you, something that actually happens.</p>
<p>There are documented examples of devices sending personal information and passwords to their manufacturers in China, which is shady at best. This should raise concerns about what devices are accepted into our homes and where they are manufactured.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="smart-assistants">Smart Assistants</h3>
<p>Virtual assistants such as Alexa, Siri and Google Assistant might seem futuristic and handy, but are a privacy nightmare. There are countless horror stories associated with these devices. One person had their Alexa activate itself and say &ldquo;Every time I close my eyes, all I see is people dying.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The companies behind these devices have admitted that snippets of what you say are listened to by humans so they can &ldquo;improve the product&rdquo;. There are cases where recordings from theses devices have been used in court proceedings. Needless to say, these devices are always listening. This is by design. In order to activate and follow a command (like &ldquo;Siri, what is this song?&rdquo;) they have to be in a constant state of &ldquo;listening&rdquo; so that they can detect the key word (eg: &ldquo;Alexa&rdquo;, &ldquo;Siri&rdquo;) and then follow through. This design can, and has, lead to accidental triggers as there are numerous words/phrases that have similar sound patterns to the trigger words.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="smart-tvs">Smart TVs</h3>
<p>Another area of concern is modern Smart TVs/Rokus/Fire TVs. These usually have Hulu, Amazon, Netflix, etc. built into them. A large reason TVs have come down in price is because manufacturers are collecting data about their users and are selling it. The collected data can be used to build accurate profiles on people and it is speculated that TV manufactures make more money from selling data than from selling the actual TV. Some TVs/remotes have microphone in them to control the system, and others even have webcams embedded in them. Both of these bring major security and privacy issues and can be used to track the habits of people using the device. Like other smart devices, many smart TVs largely go without getting updates to fix security issues.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>There is no controlling these devices once they are in your home, unless you put them onto a separate network and block some of the connections they make, which is way over the head of the average consumer, and requires regular maintenance.</p>
<p>Set good passwords for any IoT devices you own and regularly check for updates. Before letting an IoT device into your home, consider the privacy and security violations it brings and whether that is worth the tradeoff for the convenience they bring.</p>
]]></content>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <title>Web Browsers and Search Engines</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://securified.net/browsers/" />
        <id>https://securified.net/browsers/</id>
        <published>2021-11-28T00:00:00Z</published>
        <updated>2021-11-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">Browser and search engine recommendations.</summary>
          <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="web-browsers">Web Browsers</h3>
<p>Web browsers are the gateway to the internet and are what every website sees and interacts with. It is important to choose one that has good privacy (does not track everything) and has good security features. But not all web browsers are created equal when it comes to this. Popular browsers like Chrome, Edge, Yandex, Safari and Firefox are not recommended for one reason or another. Chrome and Edge are owned by Google and Microsoft respectively and have massive amounts of user tracking and data collection built-in. Safari has some Apple tracking built in and does not have some needed security features. And its only available for Apple devices. Avoid Firefox or anything based on it. It is very lacking in security features, and collects data about their users, even though they claim they don&rsquo;t. Web browsers should be kept up to date to fix major vulnerabilities.</p>
<h3 id="brave">Brave</h3>
<p>The best cross-platform web browser right now is <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Brave<!-- raw HTML omitted -->. Brave has good security features and add-blocking built in. It can be installed on iOS, Android, MacOS, Windows, ChromeOS and more. Brave is built on top of Chromium, which is also what Chrome is built on. But Brave has removed any Google data collecting from Chromium.</p>
<h3 id="search-engines">Search Engines.</h3>
<p>Likewise, choice of a search engine is also important. Google, the most widely used search engine, tracks everything searched and uses it for advertising and other purposes. It also has a monopoly on search engines as it has a 92% marketshare. This is not limited to just Google as Bing, Yandex, Yahoo etc. all do it too. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Duckduckgo<!-- raw HTML omitted --> is the best in terms of being privacy respecting and being user friendly. Duckduckgo does not collect or track what is searched or data about its users. Another good option is <a href="https://search.brave.com/default">Brave Search</a>. It is ran by the same people as the Brave browser and has all the same good security and privacy.</p>
<h3 id="browser-extensions">Browser Extensions</h3>
<p>Browser extensions (also called add-ons) are the extra apps that can be added to web browsers such as Honey, Grammarly, Google Translate, Adobe Acrobat etc. To function, they usually require permissions like being able to view and modify every website visited. With this access it can record every site visited, everything typed into the web browser (passwords, credit cards), it can display ads, and even redirect links to different websites. Not every extension is doing this, but it is difficult to verify.</p>
<p>There are numerous cases of the creator(s) of extensions selling them off once the extension has grown in popularity. They usually aren&rsquo;t sold to reputable companies, but to ad-selling companies who use the extension for tracking purposes.</p>
<p>Extensions can also be malicious. The creators sole purpose of creating it may be to <!-- raw HTML omitted -->spread malware<!-- raw HTML omitted --> to your device through it.</p>
<p>While many browser extensions are useful, a lot of them are malicious. Extensions should be kept to an absolute minimum, and only download from trusted places (like the Chrome web store if using Brave) and do some research first to determine if the extensions is trustworthy, and keep them updated.</p>
]]></content>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <title>About</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://securified.net/about/" />
        <id>https://securified.net/about/</id>
        <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
        <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">You may call me &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;. .
$ whoami $ ls -l content/ technology security privacy $ git config --get remote.origin.url https://github.com/ </summary>
          <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may call me &ldquo;&rdquo;. .</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-txt" data-lang="txt"><span class="line"><span class="cl">$ whoami
</span></span></code></pre></div><div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-txt" data-lang="txt"><span class="line"><span class="cl">$ ls -l content/
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">technology
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">security
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">privacy
</span></span></code></pre></div><div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-txt" data-lang="txt"><span class="line"><span class="cl">$ git config --get remote.origin.url
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">https://github.com/
</span></span></code></pre></div>]]></content>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <title>Contact</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://securified.net/contact/" />
        <id>https://securified.net/contact/</id>
        <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
        <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">Have a question or curious about pricing? Contact Securified using the info below.
Email Send an email to contact@securified.net.
Signal Send an email to setup communication through Signal.</summary>
          <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have a question or curious about pricing? Contact Securified using the info below.</p>
<h3 id="email">Email</h3>
<p>Send an email to <a href="mailto:contact@securified.net">contact@securified.net</a>.</p>
<h3 id="signal">Signal</h3>
<p>Send an email to setup communication through <a href="https://signal.org/">Signal</a>.</p>
]]></content>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <title>Services</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://securified.net/services/" />
        <id>https://securified.net/services/</id>
        <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
        <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">Overview of the services offered by Securified.
Packages Protected Passwords Package Password manager setup and recommended usage. Master Multifactor Guidance on how to stop would be hackers in their tracks with multifactor authentication. Web Browsers, Search Engines and Extensions Does your choice of web browser matter? Yes. Get setup with the best browser and search engine for your needs. Private App Alternatives Many of the apps you use on your phone track everything you do.</summary>
          <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Overview of the services offered by Securified.</p>
<h2 id="packages">Packages</h2>
<h4 id="protected-passwords-package">Protected Passwords Package</h4>
<ul>
<li>Password manager setup and recommended usage.
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="master-multifactor">Master Multifactor</h4>
<ul>
<li>Guidance on how to stop would be hackers in their tracks with multifactor authentication.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="web-browsers-search-engines-and-extensions">Web Browsers, Search Engines and Extensions</h4>
<ul>
<li>Does your choice of web browser matter? Yes. Get setup with the best browser and search engine for your needs.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="private-app-alternatives">Private App Alternatives</h4>
<ul>
<li>Many of the apps you use on your phone track everything you do. This packages will get you setup with alternative non-tracking apps.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="general-securityprivacy-consulting">General Security/Privacy Consulting</h2>
<p>Hourly. Some of the things this can cover:</p>
<ul>
<li>Password managers</li>
<li>Secure email</li>
<li>Secure phone setup</li>
<li>Cloud storage strategy</li>
<li>Secure network design and installation</li>
<li>Virtual debit cards - Privacy.com</li>
<li>VPN setup</li>
<li>Secure and private notes</li>
<li>Web browsers/search engines</li>
<li>Multifactor authentication</li>
<li>Private app alternatives</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="contact-for-more-details-and-pricing">Contact for more details and pricing.</h3>
]]></content>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <title>Tools</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://securified.net/tools/" />
        <id>https://securified.net/tools/</id>
        <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
        <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html">Product recommendations to aid in privacy and security.
Password Manager 1Password or Proton Pass Multifactor App Aegis or Authy Email Proton Mail Web Browser Brave Search Engine Brave Search or Duckduckgo Notes Standard Notes Messenger Signal. Cloud Storage Proton Drive or Tresorit Encryption Software Picocrypt or Cryptomator Calendar Proton Calendar Private YouTube Proxy Invidious </summary>
          <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Product recommendations to aid in privacy and security.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
<th></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Password Manager</td>
<td><a href="https://1password.com/">1Password</a> or <a href="https://proton.me/pass">Proton Pass</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Multifactor App</td>
<td><a href="https://getaegis.app/">Aegis</a> or <a href="https://authy.com/">Authy</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Email</td>
<td><a href="https://proton.me/">Proton Mail</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Web Browser</td>
<td><a href="https://brave.com/">Brave</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Search Engine</td>
<td><a href="https://search.brave.com/default">Brave Search</a> or <a href="https://duckduckgo.com/">Duckduckgo</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Notes</td>
<td><a href="https://standardnotes.com/">Standard Notes</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Messenger</td>
<td><a href="https://www.signal.org/">Signal</a>.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Cloud Storage</td>
<td><a href="https://drive.proton.me/">Proton Drive</a> or <a href="https://tresorit.com/">Tresorit</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Encryption Software</td>
<td><a href="https://github.com/HACKERALERT/Picocrypt">Picocrypt</a> or <a href="https://cryptomator.org/">Cryptomator</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Calendar</td>
<td><a href="https://calendar.proton.me/">Proton Calendar</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Private YouTube Proxy</td>
<td><a href="https://farside.link/invidious">Invidious</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content>
      </entry>

</feed>


